<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mark van der Laan</title>
    <description>Personal blog about software development</description>
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>How to get firmware on an AVR microcontroller?</title>
        <description>
          Use Arduino as In-System Programmer (ISP) - 
          Overview Okay cool, you now bought all the necessities to start programming your AVR microcontroller but how do you actually get code on the chip itself? How do you supply power to the microcontroller? In this post, I will discuss all the necessary steps. We will blink a LED to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/2019-10-30-isp-programmer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019-10-30-isp-programmer/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use AVR C timer and interrupt registers?</title>
        <description>
          C programming with AVR microcontroller - 
          Overview In this article, I will explain how to build C programs in which you can control the timer and interrupt registers of an AVR microcontroller. If don’t know where to start, I have a tutorial here that explains the basics of how to setup a microcontroller and turn on...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>/2019-10-29-avr-c-timer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019-10-29-avr-c-timer/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bit shifting in C programming for AVR</title>
        <description>
          C programming with AVR microcontroller - 
          Overview In this article, I give a short overview of bit shifting operations (or bitwise operations) in the C programming language. For programming AVR microcontrollers, bitwise operations are great to alter individual bits inside a register. Manipulating registers without bitwise operations A naive approach for manipulating registers is to set...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>/2019-10-25-avr-c-bitshifting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019-10-25-avr-c-bitshifting/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
